Xia Hu

PERSONAL INFORMATION

HOMEPAGE: xia-hu.github.io Phone: (+1) 604-720-8996

ADDRESS: Burnaby, BC, Canada v5A 2B5 EMAIL: amber.hx01@gmail.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interest lies in the understanding of machine learning and deep learning models, with an emphasis on the interpretation and model complexity of deep architectures.

Keywords: Model Interpretation, Model Explanation, Expressive Power, Model Complexity

EDUCATION

Simon Fraser University, B.C., Canada

Sept 2016 - Sept 2021

Ph.D. in Computing Science

Thesis Topic: "Understanding Deep Neural Networks from the Perspective of Piecewise Linear Property"

GPA: 3.96/4.3 | Supervisor: Prof. Jian Pei

University of Science and Technology of China, Anhui, China

Aug 2009 - Jul 2013

B.E. in Computer Science

GPA: 3.24/4.3

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern Researcher

May 2019 - May 2020

Microsoft Research Asia, Beijing, China

- Implemented state-of-the-art model interpretation approaches to deep learning models on finance applications.
- Researched model complexity problem and proposed an approach to measure model complexity of deep learning models with the idea of piecewise linear approximation.
- Published a paper of our proposed model complexity approach on the KDD'20 research track.

Software Engineer

Jul 2014 - Jul 2016

Sogou Inc., Beijing, China

- Constructed the internal Hadoop/Spark distributed platform for over 2,000 engineers.
- Added user authentication, fair scheduling, and other functions to Hadoop/Spark open-source framework.
- Established a Wechat text analysis platform based on Spark including keywords extraction, user portraits, etc.

Software Engineer

Dec 2012 - Apr 2014

Baidu Inc., Beijing, China

- Participated in building the internal cloud computing platform, responsible for the distributed storage part.
- Investigated and analyzed distributed storage systems including NFS, MFS, GFS.
- Implemented a distributed storage scheduler which increased storage utilization by 25%.

PUBLICATIONS AND TUTORIALS

- Xia Hu, Lingyang Chu, Jian Pei, Weiqing Liu, Jiang Bian.
 "Model Complexity of Deep Learning: A Survey". Knowledge and Information Systems (KAIS), 2021.
- 2. Xia Hu, Lingyang Chu, Jian Pei, Jiang Bian, Weiqing Liu. "Deep Learning Model Complexity: Concepts and Approaches". SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM) 2021 Tutorial.
- 3. **Xia Hu**, Weiqing Liu, Jiang Bian, Jian Pei. "Measuring Model Complexity of Deep Neural Networks with Curve Activation Functions". 26th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD'20).
- 4. Zicun Cong, Lingyang Chu, Lanjun Wang, **Xia Hu** and Jian Pei.

 "Exact and Consistent Interpretation of Piecewise Linear Models Hidden behind APIs: A Closed-Form Solution". 36th IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE'20).
- 5. Lingyang Chu, **Xia Hu**, Juhua Hu, Lanjun Wang, Jian Pei. "Exact and Consistent Interpretation for Piecewise Linear Neural Networks: A Closed-Form Solution". 24th ACM SIGKDD Conference On Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD'18).

ACADEMIC SERVICE

• PC Member: SDM'20, SDM'21

• External Reviewer: KDD'19, KDD'20, KDD'21, WSDM'21, AAAI'21, CIKM'21

AWARDS AND HONORS

Stars of Tomorrow Internship Program (Microsoft Research Asia)	2020
SIGKDD Student Travel Award (KDD'18)	2018
Graduate Fellowship (Simon Fraser University)	2016, 2018, 2019
 Outstanding Service Awards (Sogou Inc, Top 5%) 	2015
 Student Scholarship (University of Science and Technology of China) 	2009, 2012

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant at Simon Fraser University

CMPT 880 - Deep Learning	Spring 2019, Spring 2021
CMPT 307 - Data Structures	Summer 2020
CMPT 371 - Data Communications and Networking	Summer 2018
CMPT 276 - Introduction to Software Engineer	Spring 2017
CMPT 295 - Introduction to Computer Science	Fall 2016

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Deep Learning, Machine Learning
- Python, Java, Scala
- · Linux, Hadoop, Spark, Matlab, Jenkins